WILLIAM BOGGS

1037 Dexter Ridge Drive Holly Springs, NC 27540 Phone: 484.942.8860

Email: dev.bill.m.boggs@gmail.com Website: https://billboggs.github.io

SUMMARY

A motivated, results driven lead DevOps and Software Engineer who is eager to solve new challenging problems. Outgoing team player who strives to efficiently mitigate software issues, while enabling teammates and building bridges with other engineering groups.

- 10+ years of experience in Software Engineering and DevOps, specializing in Kubernetes and Cloud-Native systems.
- Recent focus on integrating MLOps best practices for large-scale AI solutions.
- Experience leading versatile software teams in diverse industries.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages

C/C++, C#, Golang, Javascript, Python

Infrastructure

Ansible, ArgoCD, Docker, Gitlab, Github, Helm, Kubernetes, Prometheus, Terraform

Cloud Platforms

AWS, Azure, GCP, OpenShift

Frameworks

Langchain, Hugging Face Transformers, .NET, Node.js, React

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Hewlett Packard Enterprise AI at Scale Senior Software Engineer and Tech Lead REMOTE

February 2023 –November 2024

- Tech Lead for the HPE AI at Scale Managed Services Team, driving the development and delivery
 of enterprise-scale AI solutions.
- Designed and built a SaaS product leveraging Determined.ai and Pachyderm in AWS and GCP, enabling scalable and efficient AI workflows.
- Led integration efforts to connect HPE AI at Scale Managed Services with the HPE GreenLake Cloud Platform.
- Collaborated with HPE Cyber Security Teams to conduct application security reviews on the team's software products.
- Migrated existing Determined.ai managed service installations from EC2 to EKS.
- Implemented Software Bill of Materials (SBOM) generation for all managed service components in CI pipelines
- Mentored and guided multiple software engineers and interns
- Project lead for the deployment aspect of a new RAG application within HPE.
- Led the Determined.ai release process.
- Ran team sprint rituals (e.g., planning, standups).

Senior Software Engineer and Lead DevOps Engineer

- DevOps team lead for storage support tooling.
- Deployed and maintained multiple Kubernetes clusters in an on-premises environment.
- Architected Golang microservice backend for four separate products.
- Architected monitoring, alerting, and logging infrastructure.
- Containerized legacy applications and deployed them to Kubernetes clusters.
- Maintained Gitlab and Gitlab Runner for the storage support team.
- Researched, designed, and implemented SBOM generation and validation in CI pipelines.
- Designed and implemented Support Web Application authentication system.
- Presented infrastructure design with HPE architecture review board.
- Mentored multiple junior software engineers.
- Debugged problems with legacy code running in multiple different languages including Perl, Ruby and Python.
- Worked with Cyber Security team to ensure that all storage support infrastructure adhered to security requirements.

BOXBOAT TECHNOLOGIES

REMOTE

DevOps Engineer

May 2019 - August 2019

- Educated clients on best practices regarding Docker and Kubernetes
- Consulted with clients educating them on what is needed for monitoring and logging in Kubernetes clusters
- Performed multiple client infrastructure installs using tools such as Ansible and Terraform.
- Taught Docker and Kubernetes training courses.
- Worked with multiple clients on container and Kubernetes security best practices.
- Led a client engagement for a team that was attempting to adopt Kubernetes into their organization. Helped the team migrate their WebSphere servers to Kubernetes.
- Setup CI/CD pipelines for multiple companies.

LEVVEL REMOTE *June* 2018 – May 2019

Senior Consultant

- Mentored team members on design and coding best practices.
- Worked with client architecture teams on critical design decisions.
- Lead developer on multiple Azure Function Apps in .NET core.
- Implemented the first Azure data factory pipelines for a client to transform bank and internal transaction data so that it could be consumed in a more manageable format by customers.
- Worked with client DevOps team to get the first Azure DevOps CI/CD pipeline up and running.
- Architected a caching system for a client that was later integrated with their APIs across the company.
- Reported directly to company director about the team's progress for Levvel's biggest client.

STATE COLLEGE, PA

ISSUED: JUNE 2019

EXPIRES: JUNE 2022

Graduation: December 2013

- Sole architect and developer of manufacturing test application. The test application was critical to the quality assurance of the company hardware that was released to customers.
- Designed and developed the Bluetooth module on the company's medication dispensing device.
 This allowed customers to connect remote devices such as blood pressure cuffs and pulse oximeters to our dispensing device. This then gave medical professionals using our products better visibility into their patient's overall health.
- Migrated an existing .NET code base to Node.js.
- Worked across the whole company tech stack, which included embedded device and full stack web development.
- Released mobile application to both the Android and iPhone app stores.

EDUCATION

THE PENNSYLVANIA STATE UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Science in Computer Engineering

CERTIFICATIONS

CLOUD NATIVE COMPUTING FOUNDATION

Certified Kubernetes Administrator

PROJECTS

STOCK ANALYSIS ENGINE

OPEN SOURCE GITHUB PROJECT

- Worked with a few members of the Levvel team on a project leveraging Kubernetes, Python and Jupyter to create predictions on stock and options trading.
- The system includes pulling stock and options data from IEX and Yahoo along with storing the data in S3/Minio/Redis. The system uses Celery workers to run the data pull/store.
- Source code can be found on Github at https://github.com/AlgoTraders/stock-analysis-engine.

AUTOMATED ROTOR WAKE SURVEY

THE BOEING COMPANY

• Designed a robotic system with The Boeing Company for pressure probe readings underneath a helicopter rotor. Won the Boeing systems engineering award for work on the project.